Guide to the Keith B. Farr radio history audio collection circa 1940-2008
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Keith B. Farr radio history audio collection
circa 1940-2000s
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0917
Farr, Keith B.
22 audiocassettes and 63 compact discs
The Keith B. Farr radio history audio collection (1940s-2000s) consists of audiocassettes and compact discs of historic radio programs and radio history retrospectives from the 20th and 21st centuries, some of which feature Farr as an announcer or narrator. There are also recordings about Farr's life and his career as a radio announcer in Utah and California as well as his family's pioneer history.
Biographical Note
Keith B. Farr worked as an announcer for KLO 1430 Radio Ogden between 1959 and 1961. He hosted the "Sandman Serenade" program which aired from 12 midnight to 6am, Mountain Standard Time. His program was broadcast through out the central and western United States and into parts of Canada. After his time at KLO, he worked for KVOG-TV, Salt Lake City in 1961, and then KIFI-TV, Idaho Falls, Idaho in 1963 and finally KWIN/KCVR, Stockton, California between 1968 and 1990. He now resides in Lodi, California and continues to be involved in radio by doing research and documenting early AM radio and announcer time-lines.
The Keith B. Farr radio history audio collection (1940s-2000s) consists of audiocassettes and compact discs of historic radio programs and radio history retrospectives from the 20th and 21st centuries, some of which feature Farr as an announcer or narrator. The collection includes both nationally syndicated programs and local shows from radio stations in Utah and California. There are also recordings about Farr's life and his career as a radio announcer as well as his family's pioneer history.
The materials are arranged by format type and then by subject matter.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
Manuscript materials were transferred to the Manuscripts Division of Special Collections (Accn 2319).
donated by Keith B. Farr (11 compact discs), 2007
donated by Keith B. Farr (8 audiocassette tapes), 2008
KLO (Radio Station: Ogden, Utah)--Radio stations; Utah--Ogden--Sources; Disc jockeys--Utah--Ogden--Sources; Radio--History; Media and Communication; Sound Recordings; Oral Histories; Sound recordings
- Audiocassettes
  - Dynamics of Personal Motivation by Paul J. Meyer, 1968-1974 (Cassette 1-8)
  - Golden Age Radio volume 1 (Metacom), circa 1940s
    - Fibber McGee and Molly, undated (Cassette 9)
      This cassette contains the episodes “Gildy’s Halloween Party” and “Escaped Convicts."
    - Jack Benny, undated (Cassette 10)
      This cassette contains the episodes “The Polar Bear” and "Charmichael.”
    - Bergen and McCarthy, undated (Cassette 11)
      This cassette contains the episodes “Charlie Starts a Book Club” and "Charlie Becomes a Pearl Farmer.”
    - Abbott and Costello, undated (Cassette 12)
      This cassette contains the episodes “Lou the Sailor” and “Home, Home on the Ranch.”
    - The Bickersons, undated (Cassette 13)
      This cassette contains the episodes “The Business Trip", "The Race Tack Trout”, “The Fishing Pole”, “The New Puppy”, “The New Tux”, and “Amos Does Time.”
    - Burns and Allen, undated (Cassette 14)
      This cassette contains the episodes “The Literary Club” and “Gracie Repents.”
  - Radio Reruns (TM), circa 1940s
    - CBS News Roundup: Pearl Harbor Attacked, 1941 December 01 (Cassette 15)
    - You Bet Your Life: Secret word is “Air” with Groucho Marx, undated (Cassette 16)
    - Dragnet: “The Big Switch”, 1958 December 08 (Cassette 17)
  - Earl Nightengale financial programs, circa 1970s
    - Bank Presentation, 1974 (Cassette 18)
    - How to Increase Your Sales and Profits, 1977 (Cassette 19)
    - Our Changing World, undated (Cassette 20)
  - Eagle Marketing Corporation literary recordings, undated
    - The Red-Headed League by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, undated (Cassette 21)
    - The Count of Monte Cristo by Alexander Dumas, undated (Cassette 22)
- Compact discs
  - General radio history
    - The History of Early Radio Broadcasting (Farr Productions), undated (Disc 23-24)
    - Radio Shows: History and Commercials, 1940s-1950s (Disc 25)
    - Radio History 1953-1961 (Farr Productions), 2008 (Disc 26-27)
    - This Was Radio 1-2, undated (Disc 28-29)
    - Great Moments in Radio: Narration, 1930s-1940s (Disc 30)
    - We Interrupt This Broadcast 1-2, undated (Disc 31-32)
    - History, undated (Disc 33)
    - Predictions, Keith B.Farr, 1978-2005 (Disc 34)
    - CBS News Roundup: Pearl Harbor, 1941 December 07 (Disc 35)
    - Great Gildersleeve (NBC) and Our Miss Brooks (CBS), 1949 (Disc 36)
    - Laffter and Profane, undated (Disc 37)
      Featuring Pat Buttram and Bob Crane
    - Retrospect: Vocal Groups of the 1950s, undated (Disc 38)
    - Rick Dees: Put it Where the Sun Don't Shine, undated (Disc 39)
    - "The Elvis Tapes", undated (Disc 40)
    - Ken Nordine: The Best of Word Jazz, volume 1, undated (Disc 41)
    - Standard 1950s Showtunes (Farr Productions), 1980s (Disc 42)
    - Cong. Norm Shumbay 1st Baptist Films: Keith Farr narration, 1980s (Disc 43)
    - The Rob KaCey Phye: Artist Spotlights and the Spot Showcase, undated (Disc 44)
    - Loose Change, 2nd edition, undated (Disc 45)
    - Joel Osteen, undated (Disc 46)
  - California radio
    - Bay Area early broadcasting (Farr Prodcutions), 1985 (Disc 47-49)
      Interview with Ken Ackerman and Ed Brady on KCBS' "Nightbeat"
    - California radio history, 1941; 1968 (Disc 50)
      Narrated by Keith Farr
    - Historic Lodi, F.Farr Gaylon Rowan, Pearl Harbor, 1941 (Disc 51)
    - Jay Arnold's Goldvine, undated (Disc 52-56)
    - Northern California radio demos and jingles, undated (Disc 57)
    - KBIG, KMPC 173, KCHV: Osterberg, undated (Disc 58)
    - KEWB Oakland, Ron Reynolds, 1965 (Disc 59)
    - KRE 1400 tour, 2005 May 25 (Disc 60)
    - KSFO John Gilliand Documentary, 1940s (Disc 61)
    - KSFO - Gary Owns: Man on the Street, 1973 (Disc 62)
    - KTRB (San Francisco) airchecks 1, undated (Disc 63)
      This CD contains the recordings "Rolfe Peterson Excerpt" and "KFRC/KYA/KEWB/KABL."
    - KTRB (San Francisco) airchecks 3, undated (Disc 64)
      This CD contains the recordings "KFRC's Dr. Dan: The Quake" and "Vintage Radio."
    - KTRB (San Francisco) airchecks 4, undated (Disc 65)
      This CD contains the recordings "KSFO and Al Collins" and "KSFO's Don Sherwod 2nd."
    - KWIN - Don Roberts: actor Bob Conrad, undated (Disc 66)
    - KWIN 97 Retrospect: A Look at the 1950s, undated (Disc 67)
    - KWIN 97 Breakfast Club, 1988-1989 (Disc 68-69)
    - KXKX 97.7: airchecks featuring Mike Metcalf, 1972 (Disc 70-71)
  - Utah radio
    - Salt Lake City airchecks, station identification and jingles, 1975-1980 (Disc 72)
    - Utah Radio and TV: broadcast, archives, 1950s (Disc 73)
    - Utah Radio, volume 2, 2007 (Disc 74)
      Narrated by Keith Farr at the University of Utah J. Willard Marriott Library.
    - Utah Radio 1950s (Disc 75)
      Narrated by Keith Farr.
    - KLO Ogden - Len Allen: ABC News, Arnie Wheeler (5AM-7AM), 1989 August 31 (Disc 76)
    - KLO Ogden - Len Allen: Kal Farr, Utah Chiefs of Police Association (Radio On the Go), 2004 February 07 (Disc 77)
    - KLUB 570: Lisa Farr Rigley botantical garden show, 1991 (Disc 78)
    - KSL Utah announcers tribute, 2005 (Disc 79)
  - Farr family history
    - Keith Farr's career, early years, undated (Disc 80)
    - Farr Family immigrants and settlers (1607-1940s), undated (Disc 81-83)
      Includes settlers of Weber County, Utah (1832), descendants of Sarah Larene, and a three generation timeline 1887-2007.
  - Untitled discs, undated; 2 compact discs